你要去哪里  维奥莱特
Where you going, Violet?
我去采点花
Just to pick some flowers.
别走太远
Don't wander too far.
1980年  佛罗里达州
《My Wild Irish Rose》
*我的爱尔兰野玫瑰*
*My wild Irish rose*
*世上最甜美的花朵*
*The sweetest flower that grows*
*就算你找遍天涯海角*
*You may search everywhere*
*也没有一朵花能相比*
*But none can compare*
*我亲爱的爱尔兰野玫瑰*
*With my wild Irish rose*
你好呀
Well, hi there.
你想要朵花吗
Do you want one?
你在想我为什么戴着一顶滑稽的帽子
You're wondering why I'm wearing such a funny hat.
我一直戴着这顶帽子
I always wear this hat.
天天戴  帽子都变成我的名字了
So much, it's a part of my name now.
我的朋友们
My friends,
我最最要好的朋友们
my very, very best friends,
都管我叫戴帽子的萝丝
they just call me Rose the Hat.
看起来像魔术师的帽子
It looks like a magician's hat.
的确是
It is.
这是一顶有魔法的帽子
It's a magic hat.
你想看魔术吗
Do you wanna see?
我袖子里什么也没有
Nothing up my sleeves.
帽子里也什么都没有
Nothing in my hat.
别怕  他是我的朋友
Don't worry, that's my friend.
你要错过见证奇迹的时刻了
You're missing the trick.
把手伸进去
Reach inside.
天哪
Wow!
好漂亮的花
It's so pretty.
因为它很特别
Because it's special.
说到特别
And speaking of special,
你也是个特别的孩子  是吧
you're a little magic, too, aren't you?
我手里拿的花是什么颜色的
The flower in my hand, what color is it?
紫色的
Purple.
维奥莱特
Violet,
像你一样
like you.
你不能吃花
You don't eat flowers.
可以的
But you do.
但是这是特别的花
But these are special.
小宝贝  特别的味道才最好
Honey, it's the special ones that taste best.
我得回去找我妈妈了
I should get back to my mom.
别走  再待一会儿  看看别的魔术
No, stay. Stay awhile. See more magic.
你真是个特别的小东西啊
You are a special little thing, aren't you?
《睡梦医生》
丹尼
不  不  不  求你了
No, no, no. Please.
没事的  道格
Hey. It's okay, Doc.
没事了
It's okay.
好了
There.
都干净了
All dry.
发生了什么
What happened?
你得告诉我发生了什么  丹尼
You have to talk to me, Danny.
自从我们离开...  你一直没开口说话
You haven't talked since we left...
告诉我  道格
Please, Doc.
求你了
Please.
这样啊
So,
你不讲话了  道格
you ain't talking, huh, Doc?
我们第一次见面的时候你也不怎么讲话
Weren't talking much first time I met you neither.
你还记得我们第一次真正的交谈吗
You remember the first time we really talked?
我直接在你脑海里说话
When I spoke up inside your head?
你感觉不错  对吧
Made you feel good, right?
知道你并不孤单
Knowing you weren't alone.
也有人这样帮了我
Someone did that for me, too.
有一天你也会帮助别人的  丹尼·托伦斯
And some day, Danny Torrance, you'll teach someone else.
我不会的
I won't.
你不会吗
Oh, you won't, huh?
我是说我不会再用闪灵了
I won't shine, I mean.
不能用了  太危险了
No more. It's dangerous.
有时候的确很危险
Reckon it is sometimes.
她找到我了
She found me.
她没得逞就会一次又一次地来找我
She'll come back and come back until she gets me.
你说得对
You're right.
瞭望酒店已经被废弃封闭
The Overlook's condemned. Boarded up.
孤魂野鬼快要饿死了
They're starvin' old ghosts,
所以他们来找你
and they're reachin' out for you.
她也不会是最后一个
Won't stop with her, either.
书里的图片
Pictures in a book.
你说过他们都只是书里的图片而已
You said they were just pictures in a book
他们无法伤害我
and they couldn't hurt me.
有些东西
Some things,
黑暗的东西把闪灵视作食物
dark things, the shining's like food.
瞭望酒店
The Overlook,
对我来说就是书里的图片
it was always just pictures to me.
但是你的闪灵跟我的不一样
But I didn't shine like you.
任何人的闪灵都不像你的
Nobody shines like you.
你在那个该死的酒店里
So, you in that damn hotel,
就像一百万瓦的电池
you was like a million-watt battery
与它接通
all plugged in.
被它蚕食
And it ate it up.
这个世界饥饿贪婪
World's a hungry place.
最黑暗的东西最贪婪
And the darkest things are the hungriest,
他们会吞噬一切闪耀东西
and they'll eat what shines.
就像蚊子或者水蛭一样蜂拥而上
Swarm it like mosquitoes or leeches.
我们也束手无策
Can't do nothing about that.
你能做的
What you can do
只有利用他们的贪婪对付他们
is turn what they come for against 'em.
我的爷爷
My grandfather,
是个刻薄的老混蛋
he was a mean son of a bitch.
灵魂堕落
Dark inside.
和你父亲一样
Same type of dark as your dad.
无缘无故地打我  还有我奶奶
Beat me senseless, and my grandma, too,
他死的时候我高兴得手舞足蹈
and when he died, I danced.
但他阴魂不散
But he kept on coming back.
站在我的房间里
Standing in my room.
一身灰色  臭气熏天
Suit all gray and stinkin'
在棺材里不知道长了什么霉
from whatever mold was growin' on him in that box.
我奶奶
So, Grandma,
教给我一个窍门
she taught me a trick.
她送给我一个礼物
Gave me a present.
你好好看看这个盒子
I want you to know this box
里里外外看仔细
inside and out.
别光看  摸摸它
Don't just look at it. Touch it.
把鼻子凑近  闻闻味道
Stick your nose inside and see if there's a smell.
为什么
Why?
因为我要你在脑海里建一个一模一样的盒子
Because you're gonna build one just like it in your mind.
一个更厉害的盒子
One even more special.
这样下次那个婊子再来的时候
So next time that bitch comes around,
你就有所准备了
you'll be ready.
去找你妈妈吧
Let's get you back to Mama.
丹尼
Danny!
终于找到你了
There you are.
你去哪里了
Where did you go, huh?
把我吓了个半死
You scared me half to death.
以后别这样了  听见了吗
Don't you do that to me. You hear?
再也别这样了
Don't you ever do that to me.
失踪儿童  维奥莱特·汉森
别这样对我
Don't ever do that to me.
出什么事了  伙计
Eh, what's up, Doc?
发生什么了
What's the bit?
你在煮什么
What's cookin'?
煮什么  小伙计  是你啊
What's cooking, little friend? Why, you are.
我
Me?
没错
Why, yes.
好疼  你想杀了我吗
Ouch! You're killing me!
疼
Ouch!
疼死了  疼死了
Agony! Agony!
让我看看
Let me see now.
显然这不是一只普通的兔子
It is obvious that this is no ordinary rabbit.
所以我必须想出
Therefore, I must dream up
一个绝妙的计策  别出心裁
a brilliant master strategy, ingenious...
你没事吧  道格
You okay, Doc?
如果我引诱他...
Now, what if I lured him...
-我没事  妈妈  -进入一个碎石机
- Yeah, Mom. I'm okay. - Into a rock crusher?
不  不  不  这太复杂了
Nah, nah, nah, too complicated.
是的是的  太复杂了  但如果我
Yeah, yeah, too complicated. But what if I...
又太麻烦了
Too much detail.
是的  太麻烦了
Right. Too much detail.
你叫什么名字
And what's your name
-再说一遍吧  帅哥  -丹
- again, cutie? - Dan.
丹
Dan.
2011年  新泽西州
吃  你  的  药  吧
You're gonna take your medicine.
拉开他
Get off him.
快起来  滚出去
Get up. Get out of here.
操  我觉得你打死他了
Shit. I think you killed him.
真打死了怎么办
What if you killed him?
其实我倒希望他死了
I hope you killed him.
你听到了吗
You hear me?
让我好好亲亲
Let me kiss it better.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
我去...不
What the... No.
妈咪
Mommy?
-妈咪  -宝宝
- Mommy? - Baby.
在这呢  在这
Here, here.
你可以把她的钱放回去  道格
You can put her money back, Doc.
你至少能做到这点
You can do that much.
她把我的钱拿走了
She took mine.
她可能就是拿我的钱买的可乐
She probably bought the coke with it.
道格
Doc.
《As Time Goes By》——Bertie Higgins
*依旧是那个老故事*
*It's still the same old story*
纽约州  长岛
*一场为了爱与荣耀的战役*
*A fight for love and glory*
*一个关于生或死的典例*
*A case of do or die*
*这世间总会眷顾有情人*
*The world will always welcome lovers*
*当时光流逝*
*As time goes by*
亨利希望我们能干了这瓶酒
Henri wants us to finish this bottle
-然后再来三瓶  -安迪
- and then three more. - Andi?
他说要用香槟浇他的花园
Says he'll water his garden with champagne...
是我
That's right.
趁他让德国佬把香槟喝掉之前
Before he'll let the Germans drink it.
这样可以减轻被侵占的痛苦
This sort of takes the sting out of being occupied.
你本人比照片漂亮
You're prettier than your picture.
-难道不对吗  理查德先生  -你说得对
- Doesn't it, Mr. Richard? - You said it.
你比照片上老点
And you're older than yours.
我们就在这里还是去别的地方
Are we staying here or going somewhere?
你难道不想看这部电影吗
Don't you wanna watch the movie?
我不明白这么大费周章的干什么
I don't see what the fuss is about.
聊天室艳遇
Chat room romance.
有点恶心  没什么意思
Little gross. Not interesting.
再看看  很有意思的  我保证
Just watch. It's interesting, I promise.
行吧  最好是这样
Well, it better be,
因为她也不怎么性感
'cause she's not all that steamy.
她要出手了
And there she goes.
你不累吗
Aren't you tired?
睡吧
Sleep.
好吧
Okay.
等一下  精彩的部分来了
Wait. This is the best part.
这是我第三次看她这么做了
I watched her do it three times now
还是百看不厌
and it never gets old.
睡得沉一点
Sleep deeper,
能多沉就多沉
deep as you can.
你所感到的疼痛只是一场梦
The pain you feel is only a dream.
当你太太问起的时候
You can explain a lost wallet
你可以解释为什么丢了钱包
when your wife asks.
但这个  你可解释不了
But you can't explain this.
每天你照镜子的时候
This you'll see
你都会看到这个
every day when you look in the mirror.
而每次你看到它
And every time you see it,
你都得大声地说
you'll say out loud...
"我有恋童癖"
"I like little girls."
下次你再在网上
And the next time you go looking
找小姑娘下手的时候
for a little girl online,
我希望你记得这次
I want you to remember that time
你被响尾蛇咬了一口
you got bitten by a rattlesnake.
-有点意思  -嗯哼
- That is interesting. - Mmm-hmm.
打扰一下  小姐
Excuse me, Miss?
小姐  小姐  你有东西落在电影院了
Miss. Miss, you left something in the theater.
你不想跟着我
You wanna leave me alone.
哇哦  你好呀
Well, hi there.
你想放我走
You wanna let me go.
哦  不  小甜心
Oh, no, sweetie.
我不想
No, I don't.
生日快乐  艾伯拉
新罕布什尔州  安妮斯顿
妈咪  我做了这个给你  一张神秘卡片
Mommy, I made this for you. It's a secret card.
你好
谢谢你  小小艾
Thank you, Abba-doo.
有谁能说句咒语吗
Does anyone know a magic word?
嗯  你来吧
Hmm. You.
天灵灵地灵灵
Abracadabra.
天灵灵地灵灵  很好的咒语
Abracadabra. That's a great one.
-一  二  三  -二  三
- One, two, three. - Two, three.
天灵灵地灵灵
Abracadabra.
我也懂魔法了
I know magic, too.
有时候  如果我...
Sometimes, if I...
不好意思
Sorry.
有人看到我的勺子了吗
Has anyone seen my spoons?
我也能做到
I can do that.
那太棒了  小甜心
That's nice, sweetie.
-它们在你身上  -在我身上吗
- They're on you! - Oh, they're on me?
怎么回事
What the hell?
戴夫
Dave...
天灵灵地灵灵
Abracadabra.
哎呦
Oops.
你好啊  小瞌睡虫
Well, hi there, sleepyhead.
真抱歉
Sorry.
我不得不让你睡得沉一点
I had to sleep you pretty hard.
你的心智很坚定
You're a tough one.
也很任性
Willful.
你知道吗  我调查过了
You know, I checked.
有六个男人在三个月内
Six men in three months
脸颊上都有了那种小小的蛇吻的图腾
with those little snakebite tattoos on their cheeks.
为什么呢  你可真忙啊
Why, you've been busy.
蛇吻女郎安迪  就是你
Snakebite Andi, that's who you are.
那么  我是谁呢
So, who am I?
你是个绑架我的疯婊子
You're some crazy bitch who kidnapped me.
从现在开始只有实话
Just the truth from now on.
你只能说实话
You will only speak the truth.
你是我所见过最漂亮的女人
You're the most beautiful woman I've ever seen.
老天
My God.
效果有点太好了  是吗
Works a little too well, don't it?
来做个交易吧  蛇吻女郎安迪
Here's the deal, Snakebite Andi.
你是催眠者  对吗  你能催眠别人
You're a pusher. Hmm? You can push people.
我们这可有段时间没有催眠者加入了呢
We haven't had a pusher around here for a little while
所以我想跟你做一个我将近四十年
so I'm gonna offer you a deal I haven't offered anyone
都没跟别人做过的交易
in almost 40 years.
你几岁了  亲爱的
How old are you, darlin'?
15岁
Fifteen.
Fifteen?
老天  多好的年纪
Oh, God, what an age.
女人的花季  不是吗
Springtime of your womanhood, isn't it?
嗯
Mmm.
你可不是个女孩了
You're not a girl anymore,
但你身上没有丝毫皱纹
but you don't have a single dent yet either.
地球引力对你没用啊
Gravity hasn't even noticed you.
不只15岁了吧
Not at 15.
不过男人
Men, though...
不不不  不用羞耻
No, no, no. No shame.
你惩罚他们了  对吗
You paid that back, didn't you?
这就是我给你的交易  青春永驻
That's what I'm offering you. Springtime forever.
今后的十年里  你还会保持在15岁
Ten years from now, you're still 15.
100年后  可能才17岁
A hundred, maybe 17.
吃得好
Eat well,
葆青春  活得久
stay young, live long.
新罕布什尔州  弗雷泽
喜欢吗
You like it?
抱歉  我只是
Oh. Sorry. I was just...
没关系  人们都喜欢看看它
That's okay. People love to look at it.
我们之前是把这些放在图书馆里
We used to set this up in the library.
社区项目  只不过是自谋生路罢了
Community project, just taking a life all its own.
看  我们从那边的钟塔开始的
See, we started with the clock tower there.
-是嘛  -还在建
- Oh, yeah. - Just keeps growing.
孩子们管这叫小人城
Kids call it Teenytown.
这是孩子们建的
The kids build this?
帮了些忙
With some help, oh, yeah.
一直在建  复刻了一个小镇广场
Keep it up, build the whole town square.
你是坐大巴来的  还是搭便车来的
Are you off the bus or riding your thumb?
嗯  大巴
Yeah, the bus.
很少有人会坐大巴到这么远的北方来
Oh. Not many ride the bus this far north.
除非是来找工作
Unless they're looking for work.
是啊
Yeah.
是想换个环境  还是
Change of scenery, or...
你想逃避些什么
you running away from something?
别介意  我只是
Don't mind me. I hope I'm...
对新面孔很好奇
New face is all.
是啊
Yeah.
可能我在逃避我自己吧
Guess I'm running away from myself, I guess.
哦  是嘛
Oh, yeah.
逃避自己啊  那还真难
Running away from yourself. That is a pickle.
无论去哪你都得带着自己
You take yourself with you wherever you go.
多讽刺啊
Ain't that the bitch?
房租一周85美元
Rent's 85 a week,
先付后住
payable up front.
比利替你付了前两周  剩下的你付
Billy paid your first two, rest's on you.
禁止养宠物  开派对  大吵大闹
No pets, no parties, no noise.
我挺安静的
I'm a quiet tenant.
上一个家伙也这么说  学数学的
Last guy said the same. Math student.
我甚至让他把墙壁涂成黑板
Even let him paint the wall all blackboard,
这样他就可以在墙上涂鸦他的小谜题
so he could scribble his little puzzles up there.
但他并不安静  完全不
Wasn't quiet. No, sir.
走的时候墙也没涂完
Didn't even paint over this when he left,
但我很庆幸他没有
but I'm glad he didn't
因为我能让这个件事变简单点
'cause I can make this easy for ya,
让你每天早上一醒来就能看见
so you see it every morning when you wake.
每周85美元
守规矩
你确定你要为这家伙做担保
You sure you wanna vouch for this pup?
非常确定
Pretty sure.
这是你的麻烦  比利
It's your ass, Billy.
你这是在做烂好人
Bleedin' heart, this one.
我住在一楼  需要什么尽管说
I'm downstairs, ground floor, if you need anything.
明早来找我  我给你找工作
Find me tomorrow, talk about some work.
你为什么要帮我
Why are you doing this?
你都不认识我
You don't know me.
没错
No, I don't.
但我懂那种表情  就像我说的
But I know the look, like I said.
有时我对别人有这种直觉
And sometimes I get this feeling about people.
我知道很难理解
Hard to understand, I guess.
我明白
Easier than you think.
-谢谢  -好啦
- Thanks. - All right.
准备好了吗
You ready?
她准备好了
She's ready.
这些都是什么人
Who are these people?
等下你就知道了
You'll find out after.
那个是弗里克爷爷
That over there is Grampa Flick,
他会带领我们的  躺下
and he'll lead us. Lie down.
非常好
There.
不用害怕  明白吗
No fear. You understand?
我们是真结族
We are the True Knot
我们永生
and we endure.
我们是天命之子
We are the chosen ones.
我们是幸运之子
We are the fortunate ones.
若相连  则永结
What is tied cannot be untied.
这位女性
Here is a woman.
会否与我们相连
Would she join us?
会否与我们的生命永结
Would she tie her life to our life?
会
Yes.
说会
Say yes.
会
Yes.
这一个很特别
This one's special.
她叫维奥莱特
Her name's Violet.
她剩下的不多了
There's not much of her left.
她尝起来
And she tastes...
像花一样
like flowers.
深吸一口气
Breathe deep.
非常好  接纳它
There. Embrace it.
接纳它
Embrace it.
不
No!
不  不
No! No!
邻居还没发现我们
They haven't found us yet.
他们习惯了他的哭声
They were used to hearing him cry
因为我经常丢下他一个人
'cause I left him alone so much.
所以他们什么都没做
So they didn't do anything.
他们还没发现我们
And they haven't found us yet.
妈咪
Mommy?
嗨
Oh, hey.
你说你懂我的表情
Uh, you said that you knew my look.
是什么意思
Well, what did you mean?
你生病了
You're sick.
你太累了  我能看出来
You're tired. I can see that much.
我需要帮助
I need help.
进来吧
Come on in.
我们谈谈
We'll talk about it.
上帝  请赐予我雅量
God, grant me the serenity
从容地接受不可改变的事
to accept the things I cannot change,
赐予我勇气  去改变可以改变的事
the courage to change the things I can
并赐予我智慧  能够分辨接受还是改变
and the wisdom to know the difference.
波碧今天生日
Well, Bobbie's got a big birthday today.
-三年来  一直坚持戒酒  -对
- Three years. Three years sober. - Yeah.
谢谢你  约翰
Thanks, John.
现在轮到今天最重要的人了
Well, now for the most important person in the room.
有人是新来的吗
Is, uh, anybody here a newbie?
我们可不会等你一整天哦
Somebody got 24 hours?
有
Yeah.
刚来的  是吧
New to town, huh?
是的  我
Yeah, I, uh...
不是只有你  这屋子里一半的人都有
Nothing personal. I delivered half the people in the room.
-只给新人  没别的意思  -这是丹·托伦斯
- Just new faces pop, that's all. - This here is Dan Torrance.
-他坐大巴来的  -你好
- He's fresh off the bus. - Oh, hey.
看得出是新来的
Fresh off the ground, by the look.
这儿不会批判你的  兄弟
There's no judgment here, brother.
我们都经历过
I mean, we've all been there.
-还有更糟的  相信我  -对啊
- And worse, trust me. - Oh, yeah.
如果你想要有人帮你
If you're looking for a wing to climb under,
要我说比利·弗里曼是最好的人选了
I can't say you'll do any better than Billy Freeman here.
谢谢你的款待  我
Thank you for your hospitality. I...
我有点
I'm a little, uh...
可能我不太习惯
I guess I'm not used to it.
你知道我们都说
Well, you know we say,
"在你了解某人之前你不能评判他"
"You can't judge someone till you know their whole story."
你可能以为你了解
You might think you understand,
-但  你不了解  -你不了解
- but you don't. - You don't.
你今天怎么样  还好吗
So, how are you today? All right?
火车还跑得动
Train's still running.
那挺好啊
That's good to hear.
你还好吗
You good?
还好  还好
Yeah. Yeah.
很高兴认识你  丹
Well, good to know you, Dan.
-我也是  -欢迎再来
- Yeah. - Come again.
-谢谢  -希望能很快再见到你
- Thanks. - Hope to see you again soon.
我会再来的
I'll come back, yeah.
他人真好  他有一种天赋
Really good man. He's got a gift...
嗯  比利  等我一下
Yeah. Hey, Billy, hang on.
嘿  医生
Hey, Doc.
你的手表
Your watch. Uh...
你的手表不见了  你在担心
You lost your watch. You were worried about the kid with...
患古彻氏病的孩子
Goocher's.
什么
What?
古彻还是高彻氏病  什么骨头病
The kid with Goocher's or Gaucher's. The bone thing.
高歇氏病
Gaucher's disease.
没错
Right.
你在医院的洗手间洗手
You were washing your hands in the hospital bathroom
然后把表落在了皂液器上
and you left it on the soap dispenser.
去那儿找一下吧
Well, just check on the soap dispenser.
-很高兴认识你  -好吧
- It's good to meet you. - Yeah.
你是怎么知道的
How did you know?
我也说不清楚
I wish I could say.
就是蒙对了
Lucky guess.
胡扯
My ass.
大概是直觉
Intuition, I suppose.
天生的直觉  也许就是
Like a feeling in my gut. Maybe a...
走运蒙对了
A lucky guess.
你来这里想做什么
What do you wanna do here?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说  你为什么要来弗雷泽这里
I mean here in Frazier. Why are you here?
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
做一些和以前不一样的事情
Something different than I've been doing.
更好的事
Something better.
你做礼拜吗
You go to church?
这个重要吗
Does it matter?
你有信仰吗  相信世上
Do you believe in something? Something...
有高于你的存在吗
bigger than you?
信仰不能让人变得更好
Our beliefs don't make us better people.
行动才能让我们变得更好
Our actions make us better people.
比利说你做过护工
So, Billy says you have orderly experience.
是的
That's right.
你现在有工作吗
You workin' right now?
我在小人城轮班  帮忙打理火车
A few shifts at Teenytown. Helping with the train.
我每周要在瑞文顿临终安养院工作三天
'Cause I do three days a week at Rivington House, the hospice.
很难请到好的护工
Good orderly is tough to find.
留人更难
Tougher to keep.
介意陪护临终的人吗
Do dying people bother you?
不介意
No.
我们都是要死的
We're all dying.
整个世界就是个充满新鲜空气的巨大临终收容所
The world is one big hospice with fresh air.
你好呀
Well, hi there.
你说过不疼的
You said it didn't hurt.
现在的确不疼了  不是吗
Doesn't now, does it?
我还以为自己快要死了
Felt like I was dying.
我懂
I know.
你的确是死了
You did.
你吃了后会感觉好一点
You'll feel better when you eat.
我还是人类吗
Am I still human?
你在意吗
Do you care?
不要打扰他
Let him be.
阿吉雷尔  别去打扰他
Azreel, leave him be.
阿吉
Azzie?
阿吉  过来
Azzie, come on.
快出来  阿吉
Come on. Azzie.
医生
Doc.
是你吗  医生
That you, Doc?
不  我不是医生
No, I'm not a doctor.
需要我帮你叫医生吗
Do you want me to get you a doctor?
猫到我床上来了
The cat's on my bed.
-我这就把她抱下去  -不用
- Oh, hey, I'll move her. - No.
我知道她会来的
I knew she would be.
这只猫似乎总是知道
That cat always seems to know...
到了该走的时候了
when it's time.
-看来我的时间到了  -不是的
- I guess it's time. - No.
阿吉只是一只傻乎乎的老猫
It's just Azzie being a silly old cat.
不对
Nope.
自从我来到这里  就一直是这样
Been that way ever since I got here.
这只猫知道
The cat knows
什么时候该"睡"了
when it's time to go to sleep.
大家都知道
Everybody knows that.
我就要死了
I'm gonna die.
是的
Yes.
-我帮你叫医生过来  -不要
- Let me get you someone. - No.
就算知道会有这么一天
Known it was comin'.
但还是会害怕
Doesn't make it less scary.
的确
Yeah.
但也许就像你说的
But maybe it's just like you say,
只是要睡了
just going to sleep.
没什么可害怕的  只不过是要睡觉了
I mean, there's nothing scary. It's just sleeping.
你真是个奇怪的医生
You're a strange type of doctor.
我说过了  我不是医生
I told you, I'm not a doctor.
我觉得你是
Oh, I think you are.
睡梦医生
Doctor Sleep.
医生  我好害怕会疼
Doc, I am so scared it's gonna hurt,
或者一片漆黑  或者根本什么都没有
or be dark, or be nothing at all.
-我不想  -没什么可害怕的
- And I don't wanna... - Nothing to be scared of.
只是睡觉而已
Just going to sleep.
最后的  真正的  安眠
Finally, true, restful sleep.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
谢谢你  医生
Thank you, Doc.
我不应该待在这里的
Look, I shouldn't be here.
-让我去帮你  -不不不
- Let me go get you some... - No, no, no.
这正是你应该待的地方
You're exactly where you should be.
正是这儿
Exactly.
我看见了我的妻子
I see my wife.
你好
嗨
丹  酗酒
Dan, alcoholic.
八年后
你好  丹
Hi, Dan.
我不太擅长演讲
I'm not much of a speech guy.
我就拿着这枚徽章
I just thought I'd hold the chip and
想到什么说什么吧
talk about whatever popped up.
我想到了我爸爸
And I'm thinkin' about my dad.
我五岁时他就去世了
He died when I was five,
所以我了解他的唯一途径
so the only way I got to know him,
真正了解他的途径就是当我堕落的时候
really got to know him, was when I went dark.
在我喝得酩酊大醉的时候
When I drank to dull the,
或者
or, uh,
在我想打烂别人的脸的时候
whenever I wanted to break someone's face,
因为酗酒
'cause the drinking
和易怒的坏脾气
and the temper and the anger,
都是遗传自他
those things in me were his.
也是我对他唯一的了解
And they were all I could know of him.
但现在我对他的了解有点变化了
But now, well, now I get to know him a little different,
因为他也曾经站在这样的一个房间里
'cause he also stood in a room like this once
想为了我和我妈妈变好
wanting to get well for me and my mom.
手里也拿着徽章
And he held the chip in his hand,
上面写着"戒酒五个月"
and the chip said five months
然后那一天  他
and on that day, he...
在一切发生之前
Before it all...
那一天  他最想要的
Well, on that day, all he wanted in the world
就是能站在我站的这个地方
was to stand where I'm standing now.
现在我站在这里了
And here I am,
所以  我代表我们俩谢谢大家
so thank you for us both, I guess.
代表杰克·托伦斯
This is for Jack Torrance.
查理
Hey, Charlie.
医生
Doc?
看来我不需要问  你为什么这个时间来这里了
Guess I don't need to ask why you're here at this hour.
你有哪里疼吗
Do you have pain?
需要我让克劳德特给你拿点药吗
Do you want me to get Claudette to bring you a pill?
吃药也不管用
Pill won't matter.
医生  我一点也不害怕地狱
I'm not scared of hell, Doc.
我这辈子活得堂堂正正
I lived a decent life.
其实我根本不相信有地狱
I don't think there is such a place anyway.
我怕的是
I guess I'm scared...
死后什么都没有
there's nothing.
死亡不是终点  查理
We don't end, Charlie.
我非常确定
I know that for certain.
我知道的不多
I don't know much else,
但是我知道  死亡不是终点
but I know that we don't end.
蓝莓
Blueberries.
我尝到了妈妈以前种的蓝莓的味道
I can taste blueberries my mother used to grow.
你能尝到吗
Can you taste them?
我能
Yeah, I can.
我还能听到你收音机里放着法兰克·辛纳屈的歌
And I can hear Frank on your old radio.
你常把这个收音机搁在
The one you used to have on your workbench
工作台上的工具旁边
next to your tools.
《Come Fly With Me》——Frank Sinatra
*与我齐飞*
*Come fly with me*
*我们飞呀  飞向远方*
*Let's fly, let's fly away*
*若你想畅饮异域美酒*
*If you can use some exotic booze*
*有一家遥远的孟买酒吧*
*There's a bar in far Bombay*
*与我齐飞*
*Come fly with me*
*我们飞呀  飞向*
*Let's fly, let's fly...*
*远方*
*away*
-早上好
一分钟了  小笔友
Been a minute, little pen pal.
-早上好
-该上学了  :)
艾伯拉  去上学了
Abra? School.
好  知道了
Fine, I know.
弗里克爷爷  看到斯斯了吗
Hey, Gramps, you seen Rosie?
在瞭望台上
Watchtower.
你还好吗
You feelin' okay?
好得很
Peachy keen.
抱歉打扰一下
Sorry to interrupt.
找到了吗
Any luck?
快了
Gettin' closer.
他在爱荷华州某个地方
He's somewhere in Iowa, I think.
等我确定找到了他
We'll all take a nice long road trip
咱们就一起来趟愉快的郊游
once I'm sure I've found him.
在此之前  我们
Until I do, we...
我们得开个新罐子  萝斯
You gotta open a canister, Rosie.
我们六个月前才吸过汽魂  乌鸦
We took steam six months ago, Crow.
六个月一无所获
Six months is nothing.
那个特拉华州的男孩身上汽魂不多
That kid in Delaware wasn't so steamy
就已经展现出来了
and it's already showing.
看见弗里克爷爷的头发了吧
You see Grampa Flick's hair, yeah?
嗯
Yeah.
我觉得他情况不太好
I don't think he's well.
他身体不好早在尼克松上台那会儿就开始了
Grampa Flick hasn't been well since Nixon was in office.
我知道
I know.
但我们需要进食  人人都要
But we need to eat. All of us.
罐里的汽魂不多了吗
Are the canisters low?
当然不是
Course not.
快捕到猎物  就没必要浪费罐里的了
Just no need to waste one if you're close to the kill.
斯斯
Rosie.
我可能需要吸一点  才能找到他
I might need it just to find him.
以前世界上的气魂比现在多得多
There used to be more steam in the world, you know?
别犯傻  拜托
Oh, don't be daft. Come on.
这话像他们凡人口中的那句
That's like when rubes say,
"五十年前的人们睦邻友好"
"50 years ago, people used to be more neighborly."
但这是事实  萝斯
But it's true, Rosie.
汽魂少了  也变得更稀薄了
There's less steam out there, and it's weaker, too.
不知是因为手机  还是他们的饮食
I don't know if it's their cell phones or diets,
还是因为看太多网飞什么的
or their Netflix or what,
但如今我捕获到的气味真的不多
but I am not picking up many scents these days
那些捕获到的  也没那么
and the ones that I do, Rosie, are just not that...
我今晚开个小罐让大家打个牙祭
I'll open a canister tonight to tide everyone over.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你知道的  萝斯  -知道什么
- You know it, Rosie. - I know what?
这就是你每天上来这的原因
It's why you're up here every day.
无论你怎么糊弄我们
It's why you're always up here
可这就是你为什么老是在上面的原因
no matter what you tell the others.
世界上的汽魂已经不够了
The world's not as steamy
而你在找一头巨大的鲸鱼
and you are looking for a whale.
阿戴尔  爱荷华州
注意这个小孩
Oh, watch this kid.
19号
Number 19.
这孩子是个天才
That kid is a natural.
他每次都能击到球
He hits the ball every time.
仿佛能读懂投球手的心
Like he can read the pitcher's mind.
是吗
Is that right?
瞧吧  你看
See? You watch,
总有一天  这些天才小手中会出一个
one of these days, one of those talent scouts
布雷德那样的名将
is gonna get wind of Brad there. You watch.
你好  19号
Hey, 19,
刚刚看了你的比赛
just saw your game.
你已经准备好打职业了
You are ready for the majors.
-打得漂亮  -谢谢
- Well played. - Thanks.
你回家吗
Hey, you headin' home?
上车吗  我载你一程
You wanna hop in? I'll give you a ride.
不了  已经很近了
No, it's real close.
我能行
I'm good.
没事
It's okay.
我们是朋友
We're friends.
上车吧  我们能载你回家
You wanna hop in. We'll take you right home.
你们能载我回家
You can take me right home.
你相信我
You trust me.
我相信你
I trust you.
不  求求你们不要  不
No! No, please! No!
不  放过我
No! Please let me go.
我不会说出去的  求求你们
Please, I won't tell. Please. Please!
19号
Number 19.
小子  还不赖嘛
Kid, you were good.
不
No!
不  放过我吧
No, please let me go.
我不会说出去的
I won't tell.
我不会说出去的  求求了
I won't tell. Please.
没事的
It's okay.
求求你们
Please.
你会伤害我吗
Are you gonna hurt me?
当然了
Yes.
不要
No!
痛苦可以净化汽魂
Pain purifies steam.
恐惧也可以  所以你懂的
Fear, too, so, you understand.
嘘
Shh.
停
Stop.
Stop!
停  禽兽
Stop, monster.
停下来
Stop. Stop.
怎么了
What is it?
不  停下来
No! Stop!
艾伯拉
Abra! Abra!
亲爱的  快醒醒
Sweetie. Sweetheart, wake up. Wake up, sweetheart.
艾伯拉  醒醒
Abra, wake up!
-艾伯拉  -停下来
- Abra! Abra! - Stop it!
老天
Jesus.
好吧
Okay.
棒球男孩
准备好了
Okay, ready?
他们杀了他
They killed him.
-没事  -没关系
- It's okay. - It's all right.
有个偷窥者
We had a looker.
今晚
Tonight?
是的
Yeah.
有很多汽魂
Big steam?
亲爱的  简直是汽魂宝藏
Oh, honey, it was huge.
在哪里
Where?
好像是在  东海岸
East Coast, I think.
你是说有人
You're saying someone looked in
从一千五百公里外看我们
from 1,500 miles away?
甚至更远
Maybe further.
男孩还是女孩
Boy or girl?
女孩
Girl, I think.
她一进一出速度太快了
She was out of there so fast.
但我保证  乌鸦宝贝
But I swear, Crow Daddy,
我已经很久很久
I haven't felt power like that,
没有感受到过
raw power like that...
这样纯粹的能量
in so long.
那我们需要好好看看她
Then we need to look into it.
越快越好
Sooner the better.
不然她父母会被吓到的
Case her parents freak out,
然后送她去看精神科医生
send her to a psychiatrist.
医生会给她吃药  可能会把汽魂毁了
You know, they get her on pills, could ruin the steam.
也许会抑制她
Might muffle her just...
不  给这个孩子吃帕罗西汀[抗抑郁药物]
No, giving Paxil to this kid,
就像把一张塑胶膜包在
it's like throwing a piece of Saran Wrap
一盏探照灯上面
over a searchlight.
我不知道她在哪里
I don't know where she is
但当她再出现时  她也一定会出现
but when she comes back, and she'll be back,
那时我会准备好的  宝贝
oh, I'll be ready, honey.
我会准备好的
I'll be ready.
希望你一切安好
你的朋友  丹
早上好
Morning.
你猜怎么着
Guess what.
我交了一个新朋友
I made a new friend.
他叫丹
His name's Dan.
小艾  你没事吧
Abs, are you okay?
昨晚  我
Last night, I...
我没事
I'm okay.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
我知道你的脑袋有时候就像收音机一样
I know that head of yours is like a radio sometimes.
会听到一些奇怪的电台
And you pick up some weird stations.
不会有奇怪的东西了
Nothing weird like that.
不会有了
Not anymore.
我的天
My God.
我得好好学习  如果不认真学习
I've gotta study. If I don't study...
运球跑过去  传球给11号
Running play. Hand-off to 11 and...
我要是不会这些技巧  教练会杀了我
Coach is gonna kill me if I don't get these.
为什么他不喜欢我呢
Why doesn't he like me?
发型的原因吗  我该换个发型
My hair? I should change my hair.
这个奇葩又盯着我看
The freak is staring at me again.
她到底在看什么
What is she staring at?
这个奇葩
Freak.
寻人启事
布拉德利·特雷弗
嗨  小小艾
Hey, Abba-doo.
嗨  爸爸
Hey, Dad.
学校一切都好吗
School okay?
书写得怎么样
How's the book?
挺好  写得不错
Good. Yeah, going good.
我在写有关查尔斯顿和黑底街区的文章
I'm writing about Charleston and Black Bottom.
感觉像
It's feeling like...
我要去写作业了
I'm going to start my homework.
好  很好  宝贝
Okay. Good. That's good, sweetie.
想想三年后你就要去哈佛大学了
Think Harvard in three years.
等着瞧吧
We'll see.
Yeah. We will see.
寻人启事
布拉德利·特雷弗
拉莫克工厂  乙醇化工厂
已停业  营业时间另行通知
本店感谢您的光临
Thanks so much for shopping with us today.
请记住  本店食材新鲜  竭诚为您服务
And remember, we're always fresh, just for you.
你好呀
Well, hi there.
快出去
Get out!
出去  从我的脑子里滚出去
Get out! Get out of my head!
出去
Get out!
-女士  你没事吧  -别过来
- Ma'am, are you okay? - No! No.
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
老天
Jesus.
丹
Danno?
丹  丹
Dan? Dan?
起来  站起来  丹
Get up. Stand up, Dan.
起来  丹
Come on, Danno.
-发生什么了  -你刚刚摔倒了
- What happened? - Well, you just dropped.
我以为你中风了  托尼是谁
Thought you was having a stroke. Who's Tony?
什么
What?
你一直在说"请帮帮我  托尼"
You kept saying, "Please help me, Tony."
哦
Oh.
不好意思
Well, I'm sorry about that.
斯斯
Rosie?
我们遇到麻烦了
We've got a problem.
-跟我说说  -那个偷窥者
- Talk to me. - The looker?
她又找到我了
Yeah, she found me again.
-怎么找到的  -我不知道
- How? - I don't know.
我也不关心
I don't care.
我们必须抓住她  乌鸦  必须抓住
We have to have her, Crow. We have to.
她知道你是谁吗  知道我们在哪吗
Does she know who you are? Where we are?
不  不知道  我觉得
No, I don't know. I don't think...
那不重要  听着
That's not the important... look.
我说过她有很多汽魂
I said she's huge steam,
-对吧  -嗯嗯
- Right? - Mmm-hmm.
她远远不止如此
Yeah, it's even bigger than that.
我试图在她体内转身
I tried to turn around in her
结果她把我甩出体外  不费吹灰之力
and she blew me out of her like I was nothing.
你放屁吧
Bullshit.
不  我从来没遇见过这种情况
No. Never happened to me, ever.
我本以为绝不可能
I would have said that was impossible.
我们是吸她的汽魂  还是转化她
Is she food, or do we turn her?
不能转化她
We don't turn her.
斯斯  你确定吗
Rosie, are you sure?
如果真是这样
If she's what you say she is, then...
真结族里绝不能有这样能力的人
Then we don't want anyone with that power in the Knot.
天呐  动脑子想想
Jeez. Think about it.
祝你今天愉快
Have a great day.
你也是
You, too.
嗨
Hi.
比利
Billy.
你可以听到我说的话
You can hear me.
我们用嘴说话吧  好吗
Let's use our outside voices, all right?
你直接找到的我吗
You tracked me down?
很简单  就像定位系统  但是是在我脑子里
It was easier than I thought. Like GPS, but in my head.
听着  我没别的意思
Look, I don't mean any offense,
但这个时候  一个老男人
but this day and age, a grown man
和一个小女孩坐在公园长椅上
sitting with a teenage girl on a park bench...
我是艾伯拉·斯通
I'm Abra Stone.
如果有人问起  就说你是我叔叔
And if anyone asks, you're my uncle.
丹叔叔
Uncle Dan.
这甚至都不算说谎  不完全是
And that's not even a lie. Not totally.
你会魔法  就像我一样
You're magic, like me.
我不知道什么魔法
I don't know about magic.
我
I...
我通常称之为闪灵
I always called it the shining.
咱俩都会闪灵
And, yeah, we both shine.
你父母知道吗
Do your parents know?
我会闪灵
About my shine?
他们对此避而不谈
They don't talk about it.
当我使用时  他们用不同的眼光看我
Or if I use it, they look at me different.
小时候  我不知道闪灵是怎么回事
When I was a kid, I didn't understand the shining.
我把它叫做"托尼"
I called it "Tony."
我把它当做我的假想朋友
I thought he was my imaginary friend.
我还以为你是我的假想朋友
I thought you were my imaginary friend...
一直以来
for a long time.
有多少像我们一样的人
How many of us are out there?
有很多人都有一点闪灵的能力
There's a lot of people who have a little bit of shine,
他们甚至都不知道
they don't even know it.
他们总能在妻子伤心的时候
They always seem to come home with flowers
带着一束花回家
when their wives are sad,
或者他们裸考都能取得高分
or they do well on the school test they didn't study for.
但我这辈子只见过两三个人
But I only met two or three people in my whole life
知道自己有闪灵的能力
who knew they shined.
那个棒球男孩会闪灵
The baseball boy shined.
他叫布拉德利·特雷弗
His name was Bradley Trevor.
有一群人
These people...
或者说长得像人的一群东西  他们抓走了他
they look like people anyway, they took him.
然后吃了她
And they ate him.
他们吸走了他的闪灵
They ate his shine.
你能感应到
You could feel it?
他们也能感应到我
And they could feel me.
如果你能拿到男孩的东西
If you could get something of his,
如果你可以去爱荷华州
if you could go to Iowa...
-慢着  -我可以帮你找到男孩
- Whoa, hang on. - I can help you find him.
那么他父母就能知道他在哪了
Then his parents would know where he was.
至少他的父母可以好好安葬他
They could bury him right, at least.
这样我们也能找到他的棒球手套
We could also get his glove.
如果我能摸到那只手套  我就能追踪那群人
If I can touch that glove, I can track them.
慢点  放松
Easy. Easy.
因为那个叫巴里的大块头  这应该是他的名字
Because Barry the chunk, I think that was his name,
在他们杀他之前
for a while, before they killed him,
他戴着那个手套
he was wearing it.
艾伯拉  回家去
Abra, go home.
别追那些人了
Don't chase these people.
别激怒他们
Don't aggravate them.
无论你做什么  别让他们注意到你
And whatever you do, don't attract their attention.
找点东西  什么都行
Find something, anything,
尽量遮住你的闪灵
well, almost anything, to stop that shine of yours.
低调点  然后祈祷
Keep your head down and hope to God
那些人  任何他们那样的人
that these people or anything like them,
祈祷他们找不到你
that they don't see you.
他们一旦找到  就会来找你
If they see you, they come back.
艾伯拉  听到我说的了吗
Abra, do you hear me?
他们会来找你
They come back.
低调点  注意安全
Keep your head down. Stay safe.
对不起
I'm sorry.
艾吉
Hey, Azzie.
今晚你搞错了
You got your wires crossed tonight.
那房间空空如也  小阿
That room's empty, Az.
一个人都没有
There's no one in that room.
等下  道格
Whoa! Hang on, Doc.
迪克
Dick.
我很抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry.
我以为是
I... I... I thought it was...
以为我是瞭望酒店来的
Thought I was from the Overlook.
差点把我锁里面
Almost locked me up.
那些老鬼现在还常来看你啊
Still getting visits from them old ghosts?
不了  有几年没来了
No, not for years.
霍睿斯·德文特是最后一个
Horace Derwent was the last one,
彩屑彩糖落在他的衣服上
confetti on his suit.
说"多棒的派对  不是吗"
Said, "Great party, isn't it?"
他咧着嘴笑像吃了屎一样
Shit-eating grin on his face
直到我拉出箱子把他塞里面
till I pulled out a box for him.
笑容很快消失了
That grin went fast.
有个问题我之前一直没问
Hey, it never occurred to me to ask you back then,
他们在箱子里会发生什么
what happens to them in those boxes?
会死在里面吗
Do they die in there?
你在乎吗
Do you care?
我很想你
I missed you.
很长时间了吧
Has it been a long time?
都记不得多久了
Can't tell.
世界对我已是一场梦里的梦
This world is a dream of a dream to me now.
八年多点
Eight years. Little more.
你为什么在这
Why are you here?
我在这因为万事必有终
I'm here because it all comes 'round.
我们终将回到原点  道格
Ka's a wheel, Doc.
当你是个孩子的时候
These empty devils ever found you
如果这些鬼魂找到你
when you was a tyke,
哪怕他们只是嗅到了你
if they'd even sniffed you,
你也早就已经死了
you'd be long dead.
他们吸噬他人的惨叫
They eat screams,
渴饮他人的痛苦
and drink pain,
他们已经注意到了那个小女孩
and they've noticed that little girl.
他们可能杀掉她
They might kill her,
可能转化她
might turn her...
甚至会一直折磨她直到耗尽她为止
or might keep her till she's all used up,
这也是最可怕的情况
and that'd be worst of all.
你不能让他们得逞
You can't let 'em.
为什么是我
Why me?
因为她找的你
Because she found you.
因为她主动找的你  道格  你说为什么是你
Because she showed up. Hell, Doc, why me?
那一天你只是走进了我的厨房
You just walked on into my kitchen one day,
而我到现在还得跟着你
and I'm still on the hook.
我他妈该怎么做
What the hell am I supposed to do?
她要什么给她什么
Get her what she asked for.
你不会再看见我了  道格
You won't see me again, Doc.
这是我最后一个梦境
This is my last dream.
我觉得你现在混得还行  小伙子
It seems to me you grew up fine, son,
但你还欠着一笔账
but you still owe a debt.
该还清它了
Pay it.
-嘿  -妈妈
- Hey. - Hey, Mom.
感觉还好吗
You feeling okay?
吃晚饭没见着你
We missed you at dinner.
我没事  就是今天过得挺差的
I'm okay. Just had a rough day.
早上我要飞去看莫莫
I'm flying out to see Momo in the morning.
我会尽快赶回来的
I'll be back as soon as I can.
小艾  她
Abs, is she...
这次她能挺过去吗
Is she gonna pull through this time?
我不知道
I don't know.
希望吧
I hope so.
告诉她我爱她
Tell her I love her.
接着睡吧  小公主
Keep sleeping, princess.
凡人啊
You rubes.
耗费一生做了这么点箱子
Spend your whole lives making little boxes,
这么点记忆
little memories.
你觉得这些就让你富有
Oh, you think they make you so rich.
你真该看看我的  孩儿
You should see mine, kiddo.
我的脑子是个大教堂
Oh, my mind's a cathedral.
嘿  你好呀
Well, hi there.
他说你会来的
He said you'd come back.
你果然回来了
And you did.
很好
Good.
不
No!
退后  退后
Get back! Get back!
你他妈只是个小屁孩
You're just a fucking child!
你在哪呢
Where are you?
在哪呢  你在哪呢
Where? Where did you... where...
你干了什么  你在哪
What did you... Where did you...
不要
No.
出去  出去
Get out! Get out!
出去
Get out!
萝斯
Rose?
陷阱
Trap.
发生什么了
What the hell happened?
小婊子给我设了个陷阱
Little bitch set a trap for me.
天呐你的手
Oh, my God. Oh, your hand.
萝斯  萝斯冷静点
Rose! Rose, calm down.
现在我们知道她在哪了对吧  现在我们知道了
We know where she is now, right? Now we know.
她在我脑袋里
She was in my head!
-什么  -她在偷东西
- What? - Stealing!
-她都知道什么  -我不知道  不知道
- What does she know? - I don't know. I don't know.
-她知道多少  -我不知道
- How much does she... - I don't know!
-我不知道  -有个坏消息
- I don't know... -There's a problem.
现在不是时候
Not now!
弗里克爷爷
Grampa Flick...
我觉得他要更迭了
I think he's cycling.
丹叔  丹叔  我伤了她
Uncle Dan! Uncle Dan, I hurt her.
我真的伤了她
I really hurt her.
她罪有应得
I hurt her and she deserved it,
这不是最棒的部分  最棒的是
and that's not the best part. The best part is...
最棒的是我进入她的脑子里了
The best part is I got in her head.
我在她脑子里
I got in her head.
-丹叔  你在吗  -天呐艾伯拉
- Uncle Dan? Are you there? - Oh, God, Abra.
你能听到我说话吗
Can you hear me?
你都干了点什么
What have you done?
跟她说话吧
Just talk to the kid.
既然木已成舟  那咱们上吧
If we're gonna do this, then let's do this.
嗨  艾伯拉
Hi, Abra.
我能听到你
I can hear you.
我不能理解
I don't understand.
你也会这样
You will.
我以为我们可以永远地活着
I thought we lived forever.
有人这么承诺过你吗  安迪
Did someone promise you that, Andi?
有人说你是永生不死的吗
Did someone say you're immortal?
我说"吃得好  活得久"
I said, "Live long, eat well."
我们能活很久  很久很久
We can live long, very long.
我们也可以
And we do,
至少大部分可以
most of us.
但是我们还没吃好
But we haven't been eating well.
已经很久没吃好了
Not for a long time.
萝斯  他要走了
Rosie, he's going.
萝斯
Rosie.
我在  亲爱的
Yes, love?
我害怕
I'm scared.
不  别怕
No, you're not.
你见证过帝国的崛起
You watched empires rise
和陨落
and fall.
给罗马角斗士喝过彩
Cheered the gladiators in Rome.
游历过各大洋
Sailed across oceans
发现过新大陆
to new worlds
你有吸食
while you fed on
有国王  君主  教皇
kings, and princes, and popes.
他们为你书写神话
They wrote myths of you,
树立雕像
and made statues,
人们因你而颤栗  无论在乡野  在卧室
and they trembled in their villages, and beds...
还是摩天大楼
and skyscrapers.
所以  不
So, no...
你不怕
you're not scared.
你是王
You're a king,
你以恐惧为食
and you eat fear.
嘿  老哥
Hey, bro.
现在是凌晨4点啊
You know, it's 4:00 a.M.
你一直懂我的  比利
You've always seen me, Billy.
你一直很识人  可以这么说吧
You have a good sense about people, is that fair to say?
是啊  什么事
Yeah, what...
你觉得我是个老实人吗  一个好人
You think I'm an honest man? A good man?
是啊  是啊  丹  我
I do, I do. Dan, I...
你得帮我
I need your help.
首先你得听我讲个故事
The first thing I need is for you to listen to a story
并且尽可能的相信我
and try harder than you've ever tried to believe me.
情况怎么样
How's it going?
哦  嘿  你不要去上学吗
Oh, hey. Shouldn't you be getting ready for school?
是  可我想跟着
Yeah, but I wanted to tag along.
你开了多久了
How long have you been driving?
几个小时吧  我们今晚应该能到  后半夜吧
A few hours or so. We should get there tonight. Late.
他是谁
Who's that?
我朋友
He's my friend.
可能是我最好的朋友
Maybe my best friend.
你能看见她当时的表情就好了
You should've seen her face.
她害怕了  丹叔
She was scared, Uncle Dan.
就像被她吓到的孩子们那样
Scared like all those kids were scared.
那些被她害死的孩子们
All those kids she's killed.
趁她抓狂惊吓的劲儿  我就进了她脑袋
She was so mad and so scared that I got in.
是我的新技能
That was a new trick.
我以前从来没干过
I've never done that before.
我也没有  里面什么样
Yeah, me neither. What was it like?
像个图书馆
Like a library.
我猜我们的大脑都像图书馆一样
I guess we're all libraries inside.
你怎么做到的
How'd you do it?
像这样  轻轻一推
Like this. Just a little push.
艾伯拉
Abra!
对不起  对不起  对不起  对不起
Sorry! Sorry, sorry, sorry!
对不起  我不是有意的
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to.
没事
It's okay.
那些盒子是什么
What were all those boxes?
没什么
Nothing.
骗子
Liar.
我小时候
When I was a kid,
比你还小的时候
younger than you,
我撞上了跟这些类似的东西
I bumped into something like these things
也是吸人精气的
that ate like they do.
唯一不同的是那不是人  而是个地方
Only it wasn't a person, it was a place.
那地方后来关停荒废了
They closed it down after and let it rot.
但是那里面的东西  它们...
But the things that lived there, they...
再别去翻那些盒子了
Don't go poking around in there again.
好吧  不会了  我保证
Okay, I won't. I promise.
我们快准备好了  正要上车
We're almost ready. We're just loading up.
很好
Good.
让房车上路
Get the caravan on the road
我们一两天就能抓到她
and we'll have her in a day or two.
萝斯  我觉得你不能去
I don't think you should come, Rosie.
你他妈说什么
The fuck did you just say?
她锁定过你  进过你的脑袋
She tagged you. She got in your head.
是啊  下不为例
Yeah, it won't happen again.
谁知道在你把她赶出去前
And who knows how much she got to
她已经知道了多少
before you kicked her out.
她是我的  乌鸦
She's mine, Crow.
现在  据我们所知
Right now, as far as we know,
你是我们中唯一她能够追踪到的人
you are the only one of us she could track.
如果她发现你来了
Now, if she sees you coming,
她可以逃走
she could run
或者再设个陷阱
or set another trap.
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right about this.
如果她对你耍花招
If she pulls a trick on you...
-好吗  -好
- Yeah? - Yeah.
我也有招
But I got some tricks of my own.
嘿  我觉得我们到了
Hey, I think we're here.
好的
Okay.
我试试能不能和她说话
I'll see if I can get her.
艾伯拉
Abra?
就是这个牌子  绕到后面去
That's the sign. Pull around back.
她说绕到后面去
She says to pull around back.
我会告诉你在哪停
And I'll tell you when to stop.
她会告诉我们在哪停
She'll tell us when to stop.
我不得不说  丹尼
I gotta tell you, Danno,
我不知道
I don't know whether
该希望你是对的还是错的
I hope you're right or wrong about this.
如果你错了  我的好友就成了疯子
I mean, if you're wrong, my friend is crazy.
彻头彻尾的
I mean, full-blown...
精神崩溃
mental breakdown,
臆想出不存在的恶魔杀戮小孩的戏码
imaginary-monsters- killing-imaginary-kids
精神错乱
bonkers.
但是我能应付得来
But, you know, I... I can work with that.
但如果你是对的
If you're right, though...
我明白
I know.
就更糟了
It's much worse.
你该回家了
You should go home.
什么
What?
不  不是说你
No, not you.
我能应付得来
I can handle it.
不  剩下的交给我们
No. We'll take it from here.
好了  就我们俩
Okay, it's just us.
你闻到了吗
You smell that?
我以前打猎  和你说过吗
Used to hunt. I ever tell you that?
没
No.
猎鹿
Deer.
有一年夏天
This one summer,
我射中了一头鹿
I clipped this buck.
追踪了两天
I was tracking it for two days.
射中了  重伤了它
I got the shot, clipped him.
它跑了  我去追
He ran off, I went after.
以为它撑不了多久
Figured he wasn't gonna last long.
然后它就没影了
Then he vanished.
就像蒸发了一样
Just up and evaporated.
无影无踪  太迷了
Not a trace. Truly baffling.
五天后
Five days later,
我在几里外的一个据点
I'm trying a different spot, miles away.
找可以打猎的地方
I come around looking for a spot for a blind,
然后我闻到了它
then I smelled him.
闻到了它的味道
Smelled him.
发现那只鹿
Found that buck
龟缩在树洞里
holed up to a hollow trunk.
已经死了好几天
Dead for days.
那味儿啊
The smell...
我再也没打过猎
never hunted a day since.
现在我能闻到这个味儿
This is the same smell.
比利
Billy.
哦  天啊
Oh, my God!
靠
Fuck.
靠  丹尼  什么鬼
Fuck, Danno. What the fuck?
他们都没把他埋深点
They didn't even bury him deep.
他们把他埋得很浅
They buried him shallow.
对不起  比利
I'm sorry, Billy.
你到底给咱们惹了什么事
What did you get us into?
干这事的人
The people who did that...
根本不是人
They're not people.
不  绝对不是
No. No, they ain't.
能这样对一个小男孩下手
Anyone do that to a little boy,
他们不是人
they ain't people.
东西弄到了没
Did you get it?
嗯  弄到了
Yeah, we got it.
她又来了吗
Is she back?
我们在回你那儿的路上  应该早上到
We're heading back to you. We'll be back in the morning.
但还有一件事要做
We got a stop to make.
你得告诉你爸妈发生了什么事
I need you to show your parents what's happening.
不
No.
-必须  -不要
- Yeah. - No.
他们都几乎相信我是正常人了
They almost think I'm normal.
要是告诉他们  他们会
If I tell them, they'll...
萝斯为了找到你会对他们下手的
Rose'll go through them to get to you.
你知道的  对吧
You know that, don't you?
她会眼都不眨地杀掉他们
She'll cut them down without a second thought.
然后扑向你  艾伯拉
And she's coming, Abra.
他们必须知道
They need to know.
所以  还有一件什么事要做
So, what's this stop we gotta make?
你猎鹿的步枪还留着吗
You still got those old deer rifles?
你就是丹叔叔
You're Uncle Dan?
-你以为自己是什么东西  -先生
- The fuck you think you are? - Sir...
她才十三岁啊
Hmm? She is 13 years old!
艾伯拉  我让你和他说明白了
Abra, I told you to show him.
-我告诉他了  -好吧  这不一样
- I told him. - Well, that's not the same.
要我叫警察前先揍你一顿吗
I'm gonna kick your ass before I call the police, huh?
-嘿  嘿  -别  别  艾伯拉
- Hey, hey, hey! - No, no, no. Abra.
你不配叫她的名字
Now, don't you say her name.
艾伯拉
Abra...
对不起  斯通先生  我是她的朋友
I'm sorry, Mr. Stone. I am a friend.
她跟你说的一切都是真的
Everything she told you is true.
不用  谢谢
No, thanks.
不用
No.
那些人
Those people,
知道我的女儿
they know about my daughter?
没错
They do.
他们迟早会找到她
And sooner or later, they're coming.
我们得做点什么
We gotta do something.
好吧  我们报警  找联邦调查局
All right, we're calling the police, the FBI...
这些人已经活了很久了  先生
These people have been around a long, long time, sir.
他们很富有  还有关系网
They're rich, connected.
我觉得他们根本不怕警察
I don't think they're worried about the police.
可他们在哪呢
But where are they?
他们什么时候来  我们能躲到哪去
When are they coming? Where can we go?
艾伯拉能回答这个问题
Abra can answer that,
如果她准备好了
if she's ready.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
你确定要这样做吗
You sure you wanna do this?
我没得选择
I have to.
I95公路
I-95.
巴里  乌鸦  蛇吻  还有其他几人
Barry, the Crow, the Snake, and a few others.
树叶的颜色还没怎么变
The trees haven't changed that much,
所以  也许是马萨诸塞州
so maybe Massachusetts,
-但已经不远了  -萝斯呢
- but they're close. - Rose?
没看见她
Didn't see her.
但他们已经来了
But they're coming.
这是她唯一看到的房间吗
This is the only room she saw?
没错
That's right.
我做了些变动  藏了一些东西
And I made a few changes. Hid a few things.
好的
All right.
他们会设法追踪你
Well, they'll be trying to track you,
设法跟上你
trying to catch on.
你就让他们跟上你
And you're gonna let them.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
也许吧  但你得让他们跟着
Possibly, but you're gonna let them,
然后我需要你设个小小的陷阱
and then I need you to try and do a little trick.
类似于魔术戏法吗
A magic trick?
他们跟着我们
They're following us.
集中注意  直到他们下车为止
Concentrate. You gotta keep it up until they land.
我明白
I know.
这里应该可以
This should work.
那儿  那儿都有很好的掩体
Good blinds over there, and there.
他们快到了吗
They still close?
我觉得越来越近了
Getting closer, I think.
这真不容易
This is tough.
我明白  我明白  还有多久
I know. I know. How much longer?
来吧  乌鸦老爹
Okay, Crow Daddy,
把她抓来
go get her.
你好像很放松
You look relaxed.
感觉也很放松  对不对  艾伯拉
You feel relaxed, don't you, Abra?
也许吧
I guess.
你的确应该
You should.
放轻松
Just relax.
我们是你的朋友
We're friends.
你们是  朋友
You're friends.
没错
That's right.
是朋友嘛
Just friends.
我们想带你去见更多的朋友
And we want to take you to meet more friends.
好朋友
Good friends.
切  妈的
Well, shit.
他们把你说的
The way they talked you up,
我还以为会有多难搞定似的
I was thinking it'd be a little harder than that.
什么鬼
The fuck?
把戏  都是该死的把戏
Parlor tricks. Just fuckin' parlor tricks.
不  快点离开那儿
No! Get out of there!
赶快离开
Get out of there!
不
No!
这是你应得的
You deserve it.
你们全都  活该
You deserve it. All of you.
不
No!
噢  该死
Oh, fuck.
别动
Stop.
宝贝  我只有一个问题
I just got one question for you, sweetie.
你不想睡吗
Aren't you sleepy?
你很想睡觉
You're sleepy.
睡吧
Sleep.
醒醒  丹叔叔
Wake up! Uncle Dan!
快醒醒  快起来
Wake up! Wake up.
醒醒
Wake up!
死男人
Fucking men.
去死吧
快走开  比利
Stay back, Billy.
自尽吧
Kill yourself.
不要
No!
比利
Billy!
少了一个人
There is one missing.
我没看到乌鸦
I didn't see the Crow.
乌鸦去哪了
Where is the Crow?
我在这  艾伯拉
Hello, Abra.
艾伯拉
Abra!
噢  很好  你醒了
Oh, good, you're awake.
丹...
Dan...
别费劲了
Don't bother.
你对我做了什么
What's wrong with me?
你被下了药  小姐
You've been dosed, missy.
我从未用过如此大的剂量
More than I've ever used before.
可能会让你时不时的醒来
Might let you wake up here and there,
但是你的汽魂会一直沉睡
but that steam of yours is fast asleep.
我爸爸
My dad...
我爸爸怎么样了
What happened to my dad?
今天很多好人都死了
Lot of good people killed today.
很多  很多好人
Lot of good people.
我也想告诉你  有人会付出代价
I'd love to tell you someone will pay,
有一天正义降临  会让今天这些事得以昭雪
some kind of justice raining down on the sad events today,
但现实不是这样的
but it don't work like that.
我们总能抓到你
We were always gonna have you.
我的人死了一些
Some of my people are dead.
你的人也死了几个
Some of yours are dead.
可是结果不会变
Outcome didn't change, though.
仔细想想
Think on that a minute.
结果没变
The outcome didn't change.
所以说  他们的死
So, their deaths,
他们所有人的死
all of them,
都是徒劳的
just a waste.
小姑娘  这都是你给我们带来的的损失
A waste you brought on to us all, young lady.
为了什么呢
For what?
求求你听到
Please hear me...
没人能听见你的声音
Ain't nobody hearing you.
别白费力气了  享受旅途吧
Might as well calm down and enjoy the ride.
就像我刚才说的
Like I said,
结果不会变
outcome hasn't changed.
不要
No.
拜托
Please.
拜托  拜托  拜托
Oh, please, please, please.
求求了
Please.
艾伯拉
Abra!
Abra.
托尼
Tony?
托尼  求求你帮帮我
Help me, please, Tony.
我的天
God.
好  好
Okay. Okay.
Okay, okay.
好  你总说
Okay, you always said...
你的大脑像无线电
your brain was like a radio.
你打给别人的时候总是无人应答  那别打了
No one's answering when you call, so stop calling.
听着就好
And just listen.
丹  丹
Dan. Dan.
求助
Help.
嗨
Hi.
丹
Dan.
他给你下了药吗
Did he drug you?
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我要做点尝试  好吗
I'm gonna try something, okay?
但是你很虚弱
But you're weak.
他把你屏蔽掉了
He's blocking you.
我都快听不到你的声音了
I could barely hear you.
你一定要信我  好吗
You gotta trust me, okay?
好吗
Okay?
呵  又醒了
Awake again, huh?
应该在下个服务区再给你来上一针
Might have to dose you at the next rest stop.
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
你知道的
Mmm, you know where.
草  这感觉就像是宿醉
Fuck, I feel hungover.
我告诉过你这是好东西
I told you it's good shit.
我有几年没宿醉过了
Haven't felt hungover in years.
我并不想念这种感觉
And, you know, I don't miss it.
一点都不想念
Not even a little.
向西  对吧
West, huh?
避开主干道  挺聪明嘛
Stayin' off the major roads. Smart.
纽约  克朗维尔
Crownville. New York.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是那个杀了你朋友们的人
I'm the guy that killed your friends.
很高兴认识你
It's nice to meet you.
招儿不错
Neat trick.
之前还没见识过
Haven't seen this one before.
还想见识下别的吗
Wanna see one more?
开枪射死"奶牛"  萝斯不会高兴的
Don't imagine Rose'll be too happy if you shoot the prize.
萝斯不会对这次事情的任何部分高兴的
I don't suppose Rose will be happy about any of this.
那个女人发火时
And when that woman gets mad,
好吧
well,
我感觉你知道的足以让你明白
it seems to me you know enough
你不该管这个闲事儿
to know you might wanna sit this one out.
掂掂自己几斤几两
Count your blessings.
管好自己
Go on your way.
有什么可笑的  老兄
What's so funny, friend?
怎么说呢  傲慢  真是傲慢到家了
Well, it's just arrogance. It's arrogance, really.
但是也说得通
But it makes sense,
如果你觉得自己会永生
if you think you're gonna live forever.
很明显
Stands to reason,
你不会系安全带
of course you wouldn't wear your seatbelt.
不
No!
丹
Dan?
我希望你很痛苦
I hope that hurts.
萝斯
Rosie...
非常痛苦
A lot.
你个小贱人
You little bitch.
你都做了些什么
What have you done?
好的  小屁孩
All right, bitch child.
好的
All right.
抱歉
Sorry.
打了个盹儿
Dozed off.
没事  你应得的
No, you earned it.
我们现在在哪
Where are we?
俄亥俄州
Ohio.
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
科罗拉多州
Colorado.
为什么去那
Why Colorado?
她会追来的
She's gonna keep coming.
-我知道  -不会停
- I know. - Always.
只有我们才能终结掉它
This only ends if we end it,
但我不觉得靠咱俩能打败她
and I don't think we can beat her.
只靠咱俩显然不行
Not by ourselves.
有这么一个地方
There's a place.
那个地方对于我们这样的人而言很危险
A place that's dangerous for people like us.
你和我说过的  那个饥饿的地方吗
The place you told me about? The hungry place?
对的  就是那里
Yeah, that's right.
如果那里很危险  我们为什么还要去
If it's so dangerous, why would we go there?
如果那地方对我们这种人来说危险
Well, if it's dangerous for people like us,
我觉得对她那种人也会很危险
I expect it's dangerous for people like her.
或许会更危险
Maybe even more so.
好
Good.
你知道的  她正跟着我们呢
She's following us, you know.
好  让她跟着
Yeah, good. Let her.
你爸爸的事我深表遗憾
I'm sorry about your father.
你朋友的事我也很遗憾
Sorry about your friend.
我妈打来的
It's my mom.
我该和她说些什么
What do I say to her?
喂  妈
Hi, Mom.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God!
艾伯拉
Abra,
你还好吗  现在在哪呢
are you okay? Where are you?
我爱你
I love you.
当我们安全了
When we're safe,
你能给她打个电话  告诉她我们在哪吗
you'll call her and tell her where to find us?
我会的
I will.
好
Okay.
不远了  在山上
Not too much further. Up the mountain.
计划如下
Here's what we're gonna do.
你待在车里  开着暖风
You're gonna stay in the car, keep the heater running.
我不想让你在那里面多待哪怕一分钟
I don't want you spending a minute inside there
除非是万不得已
if you don't have to.
她只可能从这个方向来
She can only come from here.
隔着一公里多你就能看到她
You can see her a mile out, easy.
你看到山的那边有光
You see lights on the mountain over there,
就告诉我  好吗
you blast me, okay?
在她来这儿之前  我不想让你进去
But I don't want you going in. Not until she's here.
你不和我一起在这里等吗
You aren't waiting with me?
我不能
I can't.
为什么
Why not?
我得把它唤醒
I have to wake it up.
醒醒  醒醒
Wakey-wakey.
高压危险
杀谋
金色宴会厅
今晚生意不怎么好  托伦斯先生
Slow night, Mr. Torrance.
我觉得快好起来了
Not for long, I imagine.
你爱喝威士忌  对吧
You're a whiskey man, are you not?
我之前的确是这样的
I was, most of the time.
这杯免费
On the house.
这曾是你最喜欢的牌子
This was your brand.
杰克·丹尼尔
Jack Daniel's.
过去我常常在家里看到这种酒瓶
I used to see the bottles in our home.
在我们真正的家里  不是这里
Our real home, before all this.
我闻过一次  像是物体燃烧的味道
I smelled one once. It smelled like something on fire,
我感觉就是
which I suppose it was.
恐怕你把我错当成别人了
I'm afraid you've confused me with someone else.
我是罗伊德
It's Lloyd.
罗伊德
Lloyd.
很抱歉  托伦斯先生
I apologize, Mr. Torrance.
我不知道其他人去哪儿了
I don't know where everyone is,
但很快就会热闹起来的
but it'll pick up.
我知道他们在哪儿
Oh, I know where they are.
你说得没错
And you're right,
会热闹起来的
it'll pick up.
希望您别介意  托伦斯先生  但您好像
If you don't mind my saying, Mr. Torrance, you seem...
被人利用了
put upon.
利用
Put upon?
被卷进别人的问题里
Pulled into other people's problems.
这种事很常见  希望你不介意我这么说
I see it all the time, if you don't mind my saying.
我们之前住在佛罗里达
So we lived in Florida.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
我和我的母亲
Mom and I.
我们再也不想经历飘雪的寒冬
We never wanted to see snow again,
所以搬到了佛罗里达
so we lived in Florida.
家里很小
Tiny place,
但很舒适  我们也过得很快乐
but it was comfortable, and we were happy.
我二十岁时母亲去世了
I was 20 when she died.
那个时候  我已经能看出来谁快要死了
And back then, I saw when someone was gonna die.
我会看到苍蝇  黑色的苍蝇
I saw flies. Black flies.
我叫它们"死亡苍蝇"  我看到它们在人脸上盘旋
"Death flies," I called them, circling people's faces.
母亲弥留的最后几周里  她的整张脸
And in those last weeks, she was covered,
都爬满了苍蝇
her whole face.
我根本不敢直视她的眼睛
I could barely see her eyes.
我  我试着去安抚她
And I... And I tried to comfort her,
可我都无法直视她
but I could hardly look at her.
她自己也注意到了
And she saw that.
喝点温暖的东西也许能舒缓你的痛苦
Maybe something warm to push away such unpleasantries.
你难道不想听吗  她可是你的妻子啊
Don't you wanna hear about it? She was your wife.
我觉得你把我和别人搞错了
I think you've mistaken me for someone else.
-我只是个酒保  -是吗
- I'm just a bartender. - Oh, yeah?
只是酒保罗伊德
Just Lloyd the bartender,
在瞭望酒店里倾倒快乐
pouring joy at the Overlook Hotel.
我可以倾倒任何您喜欢的酒  托伦斯先生
I'll pour whatever you like, Mr. Torrance.
一个人要了一杯酒
Man takes a drink,
喝下了一杯又一杯
the drink takes a drink,
直到酒把灵魂都带走
and then the drink takes a man.
是这样吗  爸爸
Ain't it so, Dad?
解药
Medicine.
是解药才对
Medicine is what it is.
真正的万灵药
Bona fide cure-all.
大脑就像一块黑板
The mind is a blackboard.
而这
And this...
就是一块黑板擦
is the eraser.
男人很辛苦
A man tries.
维持家人生计
He provides.
可他周围全是一张张嘴
But he's surrounded by mouths.
一大家子人
And a family.
一个妻子  一个孩子
A wife, a kid.
那一张张嘴吃掉了时间
Those mouths eat time.
吃掉你在这世上的日子
They eat your days on earth.
贪婪地吞噬着
They just gobble them up.
足以让一个男人生病
It's enough to make a man sick.
而这
And this...
就是解药
is the medicine.
那么孩子  你告诉我
So, tell me, pup,
你会乖乖吃药吗
are you gonna take your medicine?
我不吃
I'm not.
丹
Dan!
她来了
She's here.
走吧
Okay.
这个地方病了
This place is sick.
就像我的外婆一样病了
Sick like my momo was sick.
得了癌症
It's cancer,
而且更严重
only worse.
我们现在该怎么办
What do we do now?
我们往里面走  她会来找我们的
We head inside. She'll find us.
看看这是谁呀
Well, well, well.
你们好啊
Hi there.
等会一开始  你就跑
When this starts, run.
行啊  你跑吧  亲爱的
Yes, you run, dear.
反正我还是会找到你的
And then I will find you,
然后你就会在尖叫和惊恐中度过余生
and you will scream for years until you die.
我们走着瞧  究竟是谁会尖叫
We'll see who does the screaming.
没错  我们走着瞧
Oh, we'll see indeed.
其实她说得没错
She's right, you know.
你应该感到害怕
You should be afraid.
为什么呢
Why is that?
因为你压根不知道这是什么地方
Because you don't know where you're standing.
不好意思  这位帅哥  请问你是谁
I'm sorry, who are you, handsome?
是你杀了我的乌鸦  对吧
You're the one who killed my Crow, aren't you?
动手
Go.
很聪明嘛
Clever.
看来你进步不少啊
You've made some improvements, haven't you?
自从上次我进入你的思想之后
Since the last time I was in your mind.
你怎么知道不是我们在你的思维里呢
How do you know we're not in yours?
你在哪儿呢  孩子
Where are you, pup?
今天就是你的死期
You're gonna die here.
你这口气可不小
Mmm. Brave words, dear.
可你心里真的是这么想的吗
Is that what you really think?
就凭你想要伤害我
You're gonna hurt me?
没错
Yes.
你知道吗  你让我想起曾经的自己
You know, you remind me of myself.
我看得出来
I can really see it now.
你也有阴暗的一面
You've got a darkness in you, dear.
我们之间唯一的差别  就是时间
I think the only difference between you and me is time.
你现在还不知道
You don't know yet
假以时日
what you'd do...
你会变成什么样
for more time.
但我保证  亲爱的  你会被自己惊艳到的
But I promise you, dear, oh, you'd be surprised.
疼痛能净化汽魂
Pain purifies steam.
恐惧同样可以  你明白的
Fear, too, so, you understand.
我年轻的时候和你现在一模一样
I was just like you when I was younger.
我很特别
I was special,
独自一人
and alone.
直到我遇见一个人  他给了我
But I met someone who gave me
活着的意义和归属感
the gift of purpose, of community,
我本来也可以给你这样一份礼物
and I might have given you such a gift
要不是事情已经变成了这个样子
if things would have gone differently.
不想要
No?
你倒是充满了反抗的精神
Defiant, aren't you?
和我太像了
So much like me.
你的思想简直
Your mind is so...
不对  这不是你的思想吧
This isn't your mind, is it?
这根本就不是你的
This isn't you at all.
你只是一个诱饵
You're just the bait.
够了
Enough!
快跑
Run.
我们怎么会把你漏掉呢
How the hell did we miss you?
我们很多年前就该见面了
You and I should have met years ago.
丹尼
Danny.
这是你的名字  没错吧
That's your name, isn't it?
当你们这些乡巴佬变老的时候
Well, something happens to the steam
你们的汽魂也变了
when you rubes get older.
它被污染了
It gets polluted.
变得肮脏
Dirty.
你很清楚这一点
You know that.
我可以看到你周身油腻的气息
I see the grease all over you.
你再也不能像曾经那样闪灵了
You don't shine quite the same.
我猜是年岁渐长毁了这一切
Growing up spoils that, I guess.
说真的  帅哥
Seriously, handsome,
你躲到哪里去了
where have you been hiding?
我可以给你一个机会
I can make you an offer.
一个我很少给的机会
An offer I rarely make.
是吗  我可真等不及了
Oh, yeah? I can't wait.
真是有天赋的孩子啊
Such a gifted boy,
不露锋芒这么久
hiding his light under a bushel for so long.
你可以活很久  当然也活得很好
You could live a long, long time. Live well, too.
可以放纵自己  无忧无虑
Indulge yourself, no consequences,
再也不会宿醉
no hangovers.
吃得好  活得久
Eat well, live long.
你肯定很孤独  只剩你一人了
You must be lonely, being the last one.
这世上的最后一人了
I mean, the last one in the world.
小甜心  我可不是最后一人  还差远了呢
Sweetie, I'm not the last. Far from it.
我只是最漂亮的
I'm just the prettiest.
我想你知道我的答案
I assume you know my answer.
可惜了
Pity.
那我们还打不打了
So, are we doing this or not?
小甜心
Sweetie.
看看你
Look at that.
我好像割破你的股骨动脉了
I seem to have nicked your femoral artery there.
你会流血而死吧
Why, you're gonna bleed to death?
天啊  你还挺有脾气啊
My, my, what a temper you have.
火气真大
So much fire.
真是浪费啊
Such a waste!
也可能不是
Or maybe not.
真爽
Oh, damn.
就算你已经老了
Even at your age...
竟然还味道不错
it's so good.
你的味道像威士忌
You taste like whiskey.
丹尼
Danny!
小丹尼
Danny boy!
杀谋
如此多的恐惧
So much terror.
一生都是吧
All your life, huh?
真美味
Delicious.
别伤害我
Don't hurt me!
该死的
Damn.
这是  你不是一个人
What are... You're not alone in there.
你在隐藏什么
What are you hiding?
那些里面是什么
What's in those?
是什么特别的东西吧
Something special, huh?
他们不特别  他们只是饿了
They're not special. They're starving.
不
No.
No!
你好  丹尼
Hello, Danny.
过来和我们一起玩
Come and play with us...
永远一起玩
forever...
永远
and ever...
and ever.
丹叔叔
Uncle Dan.
丹叔叔  结束了吗
Uncle Dan, is it done?
她死了吗
Is she dead?
很棒的派对  不是吗
Great party, isn't it?
艾伯拉
Abra!
你试试
Try it.
你在这儿啊
There you are.
艾伯拉
Abra.
你真不乖  非常不乖
You've been very, very bad.
你不是丹叔叔
You're not Uncle Dan.
这是张面具  是个假脸
You're a mask. A false face.
那我会是谁
Who else would I be?
你是这个酒店
You're the hotel.
但他仍然在里面
But he's still in there.
那就揭开面具
Mask is off, then.
你在笑什么
Why are you smiling?
因为你不知道你现在站在何处
Because you don't know where you're standing.
我了解这些走廊就像了解我的脸一样  孩子
I know these halls like my own face, child.
我是指你站在谁的身体里
I mean the body you're standing in.
戴着谁的脸
The face you're wearing.
那是丹·托伦斯  而你不了解他
That's Dan Torrance, and you don't know him.
丹·托伦斯
Dan Torrance.
Dan Torrance
一到这儿就立即去了一个地方
made one stop as soon as he got here.
去了锅炉房
To the boiler room.
是你
There you are.
你应该逃跑的
You were supposed to run.
我不想扔下你
I didn't wanna leave you.
我就在我该在的地方
I'm exactly where I'm supposed to be.
我不能坚持更长时间了
I can't hold it off for much longer.
艾伯拉  赶紧跑
Abra, you need to run.
不
No.
没有你  我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere without you.
我得在后面关上门  对吧
I have to close the door behind us, right?
跑  快跑
Run! Run!
拜托  丹叔叔
Come on, Uncle Dan.
快出来
Get out of there.
快点
Come on.
火蔓延得很快
The fire spread fast,
毁了酒店
destroying the hotel.
净化了一切
Purifying it.
我几乎都能听见它
I could almost hear it
在尖叫
screaming.
我能听见它慢慢死去
I could hear it dying.
而在内心深处  我知道
And deep inside, I knew...
我知道你没事
I knew you were okay.
很抱歉我让你陷入险境
I'm sorry I put you in danger.
那是唯一的办法
It was the only way.
我知道
I know.
你觉得
Do you think she was right
她说她不是最后一人  是真的吗
when she said she wasn't the last one?
这世界是个饥饿的地方
The world's a hungry place.
暗黑之地
A dark place.
可能还有更多他们的同类  甚至更糟
Maybe there's more of them or things like them or worse,
但也有更多像你这样的人
but there are more people like you, too.
站出来的人
People who stand.
我第一次见到你的时候说过
I told you when I first met you...
我说过你应该躲起来
I told you that you should hide.
你应该低调
That you should keep your head down.
不要使用闪灵的能力
Keep your shine out of sight.
但我错了
But I was wrong.
尽情闪灵吧  艾伯拉·斯通
Shine on, Abra Stone.
尽情闪灵
You shine on.
晚饭好了
Dinner's ready.
你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
没有人
No one.
那不是真的
That's not true.
我在跟丹说话
I was talking to Dan.
死亡并不是终点
We go on after.
并不是
We go on.
他一切都好
And he's okay.
爸爸也是
So is Daddy.
他真的很好
He really is.
很好
Good.
来吃饭吗  宝贝
You coming, sweetheart?
马上
In a minute.